

ASPIRATION FOCUS

To pursue a challenging career and be a part of progressive organization that gives a scope to enhance my knowledge and utilizing my technical, analytical and team building skills towards the growth of the organization.

To excel in my field through hard work, dedication, skills and perseverance.

PROFILE

Engineering graduate in Information Science, having 2+ years of professional experience in application development, product development using ASP.NET Core, .NET Framework, SQL Server, JavaScript Frameworks and Azure. Strong consulting professional, conversant with new age technologies, scripting and web performance testing.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 9741377887

EMAIL:

shivanibagavathi28@gmail.com

N B SHIVANI BAGAVATHI

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

ASP .NET Core

Intermediate

.NET Framework

Intermediate

SQL Programming (SQL

Server)

Intermediate

HTML, CSS

Intermediate

Web performance testing and Load Testing

Beginner

JavaScript (ES6)

Beginner

XML

Beginner

Active Directory

Beginner

MS Excel, PowerPoint,

Word

Intermediate

C# and .NET Programming

Intermediate

C/C++ Programming

Beginner

Entity Framework Core

Intermediate

React JS

Beginner

Angular 2+

Beginner

Azure Cloud (Azure App

services, Azure Cosmos

DB, Azure storage

accounts, Logic Apps,

Function Apps)

Beginner

ADO .NET

Beginner

DBMS & Data Structures

Intermediate

HOBBIES

- Carnatic Vocal music
- Classical dancing Bharatanatyam
- Sketching/Painting
- Playing badminton, cricket, basketball
- Travelling

PERSONAL PROFILE

DATE OF BIRTH:

11 January 1997

GENDER:

Female

LANGUAGES KNOWN:

English, Hindi, Tamil, Kannada, Sanskrit.

REST API Bootstrap 4
Intermediate Beginner

Azure Active Directory

Beginner

JSON Intermediate

WORK EXPERIENCE

One Identity Technology Systems India Private Limited

as Software Engineer Associate Developer

from January 2020 – August 2020.

Worked at **One Identity** – Bangalore as part of Research and Development team, which involved product development mainly using .NET Framework, ADO .NET, C# programming, C++ programming, JavaScript, XML programming, PowerShell scripting and SQL Server (SSMS). This project involved concepts of Active Directory, Azure tenants, domains, users, applications, exchange online tools and other resources. This project followed scrum based agile system using Azure DevOps to track and update the work.

My focused **role** at One Identity was:

CAD

My work was discussed in the management forum and appreciated.

Neudesic Technologies Private Limited

as Associate Consultant

from June 2018 - December 2019.

Worked at **Neudesic** – Hyderabad, Bangalore for multiple projects for a year, which involved working on code and application development mainly using ASP .NET Core (for creating Web API and services), .NET Framework, Fluent APIs for backend solutions, Angular 6, 7, HTML, CSS, React JS, ES6 (JavaScript), Kendo UI operations for client application, SQL Server (SSMS), No SQL using Azure Cosmos DB and Azure SQL for database storage and Microsoft Azure App services for hosting the web application and Azure function apps. These projects also involved testing the API using third party interfaces such as Swagger and Postman. One of the projects involved web performance and load testing using Visual Studio extensions for test agents and test controllers, **Fiddler** and **Stress Stimulus** tests.

These projects followed scrum based agile system using TFS, Azure DevOps and VSTS to track and update the work. I was also a **full stack developer** in one of the projects assigned to me. I had additionally taken up the role of a **Business Analyst** in one of the internal projects for a period of time.

My focused roles at Neudesic were:

- CAD
- Performance Tester
- CM Intern

I organized many events such as technical workshops, seminars and Tech talks by different communities inside Neudesic as a **CM intern** as a part of **professional development team**.

I started and headed an initiative in Neudesic that promoted public speaking that followed Toastmasters style sessions called as "Art of Speaking".

I am currently learning **Customer Relationship Management** (CRM) – Microsoft Dynamics 365.

Vijay Karnataka

as Intern

from January 2018 – February 2018.

Worked as an Intern at Vijay Karnataka – Metropolitan Media Company Limited, Bangalore. I worked on creating a mobile application using online drag and drop tool that used basic programming and OOPS concepts. I worked on the design and mockups for the application and screens as well. This application used two factor authentication, generated reports and statistics of the contents that were published on day-to-day basis and provided access based on different managerial levels and departments.

My focused role at Vijay Karnataka was :

Application Developer

SKILLS

- Team player
- Good communication skills
- Good leadership skills
- Cohesive thinking
- Flexible to learn and experiment with new technologies
- Good grasping capacity
- Good observation and analytical skills

PROJECTS

- Worked on Hospital Management System using C language.
- Worked on Cross Tenant Access Control (CTAC) model using cloud computing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E). Information Science (2014-2018)

Reva Institute of Technology & Management, Bangalore. CGPA/Class/Percentage – 64.8% First Class

Pre-University (XII) - (2012-2014)

CMR National PU College, Bangalore. CGPA/Class/Percentage – 67% First Class

X (CBSE) - (2011-2012)

SJR Public School, Bangalore. Cumulative Grade Point Average– 9/10

AREAS OF INTEREST

- Programming/ Development (CAD)
- CRM Development
- Database management
- Cloud technologies
- Web Performance

WORKSHOPS, CERTIFICATIONS AND TECHNICAL EVENTS

- Completed Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900 certification by Microsoft in August 2020.
- Attended a workshop on "Web Development" by My Captain- The Climber community.
- Completed an Oracle certified course in Java and SQL from Aptech.
- Pursuing an online certification course in Node JS from Udemy.
- Learning GCP certification courses from Udemy.
- Attended many online workshops on Microsoft tools.

- Learning Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM from Pluralsight and Microsoft Docs.
- Completed online courses on C# and .NET
 Programming by Microsoft Virtual Academy and Pluralsight.
- Attended a workshop on "Ancient and Vedic Mathematics".
- Attended technical training by Aricent.
- Attended additional technical training by NASSCOM and i-prime Athena.
- Participated in "Paper Presentation" REVAMP 2015.
- Participated in "Innovative Ideas" UTSAHA 2015.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Led the throw ball team at Intra college level and secured runner-up.
- Active participation in cultural and sports events throughout college and school level.
- Event organizer REVAMP-2016, REVAMP-2017.
- Actively participated in social events by "Win Bangalore Back"
- Participated in District Level Athletics in U-16 category.
- Vice-president of Student Civic Awareness unit at school level.
- Active participation in NIIT exams and Olympiads.